What is my trading strategy? What is the secret sauce that Socrates uses?
My methodology to trading is so elementary. It's so simple
My daughter is eight years old and she pretty much understands the basics and concepts of what I do when I enter the market
So further I do here is my strategy trading strategy is a system that I put together that kind of helps me
Know what I want to look for when I'm taking my trades now on the technical side and the charting side
My system is is I would be specifically waiting for the charts or the price to
Reach some sort of key level our previous area where price has pivoted and that is the only thing that
My eyes are looking for on any time frame is a pivot a break
Are we near an area of supply? Are we near an area of demand? Are we near daily high at daily low?
Did we touch that London close that New York close?
Those are all potential areas where I could either exit or enter trades on any time frame now
When I'm starting my day, we start I start at the weekly then I move down the weekly the daily
The four hour the one hour 30 minute the five minute lately
I have been taking trades strictly on the one hour
But mainly I'm looking on the five minute to take my entries and my exits
But now that we have the simplest side out of what I look for in trading because that's pretty much it is
Once our candle reaches one of these
One of these key levels are pivots all I would need to enter the trade then would be
Strong volume following suit are what's happening in the world do is their earnings is their news
Is there some missiles being shot overseas because I mean realistically when we're trading futures all of that matters
Now that we got the technical side of what I really do my system puts my
Stragity all together and now what my system is is I go into every day with a
Number that I want to make and another willing to lose a number that I am
Accepted in my head that if I hit this it's okay. It's my losing day
I'm not gonna get upset and that's how I go
I like to take between one and four trades a day
Now I don't have to trade every day
But I'm just giving you a general statement is I like to take one to four trades a day
And I like to target between five and five thousand dollars a day
Now if I take two losing trades in a row
My trading day is done and also on all and each and one of my trading accounts live proper
I have a set number that it'll it will lock me out of trading so I can never go below a
Certain number and that number is four thousand dollars
So realistically the most money that I could ever lose in one day is only four thousand dollars
if I stick to my plan and follow my rules and
Trading you're gonna realize it's you're gonna waste a lot of time and money on the wrong sort of information and bullshit
When realistically the only thing that's ever happening and why this candle is moving up and down and we're seeing these fluctuations is
Somewhere someone is pressing this buy button and there it could be as retail
D-Gen traders, but it's probably a institution bank doing it in a calculated manipulated way. This is why I
use previous price action in history
aligned with current price action history because
The market is the flow of human sentiment and history always repeats itself
And that's something you will as well learn in your trading journey, but guys, there's a lot of bullshit and noise
So hopefully you know my content is clearing the air for you now again
I am not I was not born into
Into a smart household. I was not intelligent. I was a high school dropout. I've been to jail
You don't need intelligence to follow along on the system that I had created
It's not rocket science. It's I'm someone that realizes and no matter what I'm doing in every trade that I take
I could potentially lose this money that I could be wrong and
it'll put
Once we fall once we have our system in place
It kind of alleviates that fear and stress because if you know you're someone that okay
I can really sit and listen to myself
You're how can you lose? You're only gonna lose when you let greed overtake your picture or overtake the system
Are you don't listen to yourself ultimately every issue that involves in trading comes back to
You and your mindset in what you do and the choices that you make if you made $500
within 12 minutes of trading and you continue to trade
Come on, you know, I'm saying consistency base hits till we have that cushion and when we have that cushion
Then you can take more risk and build that buffer up like you really want but yeah, it's my strategy guys
I am not sitting there waiting for FBG's. I'm not sitting there waiting for order blocks to be filled
I'm waiting to touch specific key levels and other key levels that I'm looking for it's an indicator on trade view
that's free and
Yeah, I don't change any of the settings again all I need is volume and an understanding of
The asset that I'm trading now again. I'm trading gold
So some things I could look at while to help me make decisions are staying trades are entered trades are
Anything related to it is gold. I would be looking at the dollar the dollars up gold is down or we can look at your other metals
Maybe silver maybe platinum
Maybe copper
You can also look at worldwide news because gold is a real asset and the dollar is just paper monopoly money
But um, yeah, if you didn't know that go get yourself a basic education and yeah, guys
That is my system. That is my strategy and ultimately my strategy only works if this is here with me
What I mean by that is my mental is on point. I'm
Confident in the day my emotions are in check and I'm not letting them get the best of me
I'm not letting greed get the best of me, but ultimately I'm following my rules that I set for myself
So I will only lose if I do not follow my rules
Which would be probably be greed are you wanting more?
But uh, yeah
Give me a like and subscribe if you thought that this video resonated with what you're trying to hear and
Give me a comment below on what you guys want to see more from me moving forward again
This is probably my fifth video now that I've posted on a serious note for YouTube
And I would like to continue doing this, but I would love to know what you guys would like to see personally, so uh
Thank you for listening. Hopefully you'll continue to join it